why am i on the street
내가 왜 길거리에 있지?
Ji Tong appears
지통이 등장
Catch Ji Tong quickly
빨리 지통을 잡아라
Ji Tong?
지통?
What's going on
무슨 일이야?
What's going on with this sound?
이 소리는 어떻게 되나요?
Is there something wrong with my ears?
내 귀에 문제가 있는 걸까요?
What's going on
무슨 일이야?
Why are you the way you are?
당신은 왜 그런가요?
why your voice
왜 네 목소리야?
How could I become you
내가 어떻게 네가 될 수 있겠어?
What the hell is going on
도대체 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까
How long do I have to wait?
얼마나 기다려야 하나요?
Why don't you wake up? Why is this not a dream?
왜 일어나지 않니? 왜 이것은 꿈이 아닌가?
Why on earth…
도대체 왜…
How could I be in the body of an official?
내가 어떻게 공무원의 몸이 될 수 있겠습니까?
Go back to where you came from
왔던 곳으로 돌아가세요
I want to go back to my own place
나는 내 자리로 돌아가고 싶다.
But...where is this
그런데... 여기가 어디야?
Please tell the Empress of the Middle Temple
중궁황후에게 전해주세요
It's an urgent matter related to my marriage
결혼과 관련해 급한 일이에요
Yes
예
Could you please give me some advice?
조언 좀 부탁드려도 될까요?
Meet again
다시 만나
listen to her
그녀의 말을 들어라
It must be a woman I know
내가 아는 여자임에 틀림없어
Fortunately...nice to meet you?
다행히...만나서 반가웠나요?
This time you remember me
이번에는 당신이 나를 기억합니다
Didn't you recognize it last time?
저번에 못 알아보셨나요?
Of course I remember
물론 기억해요
I lost my way for a moment
잠시 길을 잃었어요
May I ask where this is?
여기가 어디인지 물어봐도 될까요?
This is naturally the palace
당연히 궁이네
Ah...in the palace?
아...궁전에서요?
Yes, Miyazato
응, 미야자토
In the palace? Is this in the palace?
궁전에서요? 여기가 궁전에 있나요?
The palace where the king lives?
왕이 사는 궁전?
Why is it in the palace?
왜 궁전에 있는 걸까요?
I’m not familiar with this place, and I don’t know where the exit is.
저는 이곳이 익숙하지도 않고, 출구가 어디인지도 모릅니다.
You just said you knew me
방금 넌 나를 안다고 했어
So can you do me a favor?
그럼 나한테 부탁 좀 해줄 수 있어?
Good
좋음
Of course I would be happy to receive your help last time...
물론 지난번에 당신의 도움을 받으면 기쁘겠지만…
thank you
감사합니다
Where is the next door?
옆집은 어디인가요?
Over there is Xieshengmen
저기 Xieshengmen이 있습니다
Sorry, could you please hurry up?
죄송합니다. 서둘러 주시겠어요?
I'm in a hurry
나는 급하다
OK
알았어
Really like two restless ponies
정말 불안한 두 마리의 조랑말처럼
But so strange
그런데 너무 이상해요
Why does that man look more and more like my son?
왜 저 사람은 점점 내 아들과 닮아가는 걸까요?
The slave is frightened
노예는 겁에 질려
Invite Judge Xu to come over
Xu 판사를 집으로 초대하세요
Thanks to you, I was able to come out smoothly
덕분에 순조롭게 나올 수 있었어요
Then you can let go now
그럼 이제 놓아도 돼
I was impatient. I'm sorry.
나는 참을성이 없었다. 죄송합니다.
Why are you entering the palace so late?
왜 이렇게 늦게 궁전에 들어가시나요?
It seems something big happened in the Robbery Bureau
강도국에서 큰 일이 있었던 것 같아요
I think so
나는 그렇게 생각한다
I'll just go by myself next time
다음엔 그냥 나 혼자 갈게
Thank you very much today
오늘 정말 고마워요
Hailin
하이린
My name is Hailin
내 이름은 하이린이에요
It's the Shen family...
센 가족이군요...
My brother is the promotion officer of Huimin Department
내 동생은 희민과 홍보담당이다
Are you the sister of Mr. Ti Tiao?
Ti Tiao 씨의 여동생이신가요?
You look nothing alike
당신은 하나도 닮지 않았어
you are beautiful
당신은 아름답습니다
I'll take my leave first
나 먼저 이만 떠날게
See you next time
다음에 또 만나요
hope you can remember my name
내 이름을 기억해줬으면 좋겠어
why are you here
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Did you get the news so quickly?
소식을 너무 빨리 접하셨나요?
No
아니요
what
뭐
I mean... I happened to be around here on business.
내 말은... 난 우연히 여기에 사업차 왔었단 말이야.
That's what I threw into the well
그게 내가 우물에 던진 거야
Found it so quickly
너무 빨리 찾았어요
That's Ji Tong's thing
그게 지통의 일이야
Tonight, I will give you a lecture
오늘 밤에는 내가 강의를 해줄게
Killed by Ji Tong
지통에게 살해당함
Really?
정말요?
two hours ago
두 시간 전
He sneaked into Da Sijian's mansion and escaped
그는 Da Sijian의 저택에 몰래 들어가 탈출했습니다.
It seems that he was injured near here.
이 근처에서 부상을 입은 것 같습니다.
Did you shed so much blood?
피를 그렇게 많이 흘렸나?
Difficulty moving due to injury
부상으로 인해 이동이 어려움
So I abandoned the Baiding mask and the Yako
그래서 바이딩 가면과 야코를 버렸어요
He changed back to his original appearance and ran away.
원래의 모습으로 돌아와서 도망쳤습니다.
He must have been unconscious for a long time
그는 오랫동안 의식을 잃었나 봐요
Have you woken up?
일어났나요?
Someone still took me away
아직도 누군가 나를 데려갔어
Jiang is an official. Listen carefully.
장씨는 공무원이다. 잘 들어보세요.
Ji Tong was framed
지통이 액자에 걸렸다
Framed?
액자?
Think about it
생각해 보세요
last winter
지난 겨울
Those gangsters from Yuncong Street were caught stealing silk
운총거리의 그 깡패들이 비단을 훔치다 붙잡혔습니다
Then they lied that Ji Tong stole it and gave it to them.
그런 다음 그들은 Ji Tong이 그것을 훔쳐서 그들에게 주었다고 거짓말을 했습니다.
I remember
나는 기억한다
People from the business group recognized one of the gangsters
비즈니스 그룹의 사람들은 갱스터 중 한 명을 알아 보았습니다.
Ji Tong was cleared of charges
Ji Tong은 혐의가 면제되었습니다
More than that
그 이상
Rumors also say that Ji Tong is a criminal who kidnapped the bride.
지통이 신부를 납치한 범인이라는 소문도 있다.
Abducted the daughter-in-law of Da Si Xian Mansion
Da Si Xian Mansion의 며느리를 납치했습니다.
Later it was found out that she was the daughter-in-law of Da Si Xianfu
나중에 알고 보니 그녀는 Da Si Xianfu의 며느리였습니다.
Eloped with the teacher
선생님과 함께 떴다
Is there anyone else using Ji Tong’s name?
Ji Tong 이름을 사용하는 사람이 또 있나요?
Unexpectedly, he even used Ji Dong's name to kill people.
뜻밖에도 지동의 이름을 이용해 사람을 죽이는 일까지 벌어졌다.
In short
요컨대
You just need to follow the evidence and investigate
증거를 추적해서 조사하면 됩니다
Don't be led away by fake blood letters
가짜 혈통에 속지 마세요
obey
복종하다
Those old cases just mentioned
방금 언급한 오래된 사례들
I never reported to you
난 너한테 보고한 적 없어
How do you know the details and even the blood letter?
자세한 내용은 물론 혈통까지 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
I think I heard it on the road.
길에서 들었던 것 같아요.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
Is there anyone found unconscious nearby?
근처에 의식을 잃은 사람이 있나요?
No
아니요
But…
하지만…
did you drink
술 마셨어?
Probably
아마도
I heard that Dr. Hong’s wedding is today
오늘 홍 박사님 결혼식이 있다고 들었는데
Is it because of this?
이것 때문인가요?
I'm leaving
나는 떠난다
where are you going
어디로 가시나요?
We’ll talk about it later. Wait a minute.
나중에 그것에 대해 이야기하겠습니다. 잠깐 기다려요.
Without Judge Xu accompanying me...
Xu 판사도 동행하지 않고...
Your Majesty
폐하
It turns out to be here
여기에 있는 것으로 밝혀졌습니다
It seems that even the doctor has been here
의사도 여기 있었던 것 같아
Who brought me back?
누가 나를 다시 데려왔나요?
Only we know about this, don't let any rumors leak about it
이건 우리만 아는 사실이니 루머가 새어나가지 않게 해주세요
If word got out that the bride fainted outside her home
신부가 집 밖에서 기절했다는 소식이 전해지면
It will only make the boss even more unhappy
그러면 사장은 더욱 불행해질 것이다
Okay, got it
알겠습니다. 알겠습니다
Fortunately, I was discovered by the proprietress.
다행히 여주인에게 발견되었습니다.
I don't know what she is doing there
그 사람이 거기서 뭘 하고 있는지 모르겠어
Anyway, her husband is dead, so is she planning to run away?
어쨌든 남편이 죽었으니 도망칠 생각인가?
Shut up
닥쳐
Hello…
안녕하세요…
Wake up
일어나
Why don't you wake up?
왜 일어나지 않니?
My heart is still beating
내 심장은 아직도 뛰고 있어요
Is there anyone inside?
안에 사람 있어요?
Could it be an empty shell?
빈 껍질이 아닐까?
Is anyone here?
여기 누구 있어요?
Is anyone home?
집에 누구 있어요?
What?
무엇?
Have you changed it back?
다시 바꾸셨나요?
Sure enough, I was just dreaming
물론이지, 난 그냥 꿈을 꾸고 있었어
If it really comes back
정말 다시 돌아온다면
Will it still look like this face?
아직도 이 얼굴로 보이나요?
who are you?
누구세요?
The person who is speaking now
지금 말하고 있는 사람
Is he the owner of this face?
저 사람이 이 얼굴의 주인인가?
Are you the ancestor of the Hong family?
홍씨 가문의 조상이신가요?
What the hell is going on
도대체 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까
Have we really exchanged souls?
우리는 정말 영혼을 교환한 걸까?
Is this reasonable?…
이게 합리적인가?…
Does your head hurt?
머리가 아프니?
How did the head hurt?
머리는 어떻게 아팠나요?
The road was too dark at night and I fell heavily when I went out.
밤에는 길이 너무 어두워서 나갈 때 심하게 넘어졌습니다.
how did you get here
여기 어떻게 왔어?
As soon as I opened my eyes, I fell down again
눈을 뜨자마자 또 쓰러졌어
Before that, Da Si Jian’s servants had been here.
그 전에는 Da Si Jian의 하인들이 여기에 있었습니다.
It seems that he doesn't know that I am Ji Dong
그 사람은 제가 지동인 걸 모르는 것 같아요
Wow…
와…
I can actually be so unfamiliar with my face
사실 내 얼굴이 너무 낯설 수도 있는데
each other
서로
Let’s find a way to change it back first.
먼저 다시 바꾸는 방법을 찾아보겠습니다.
We need to get out of here first
우리 먼저 여기서 나가야 해
Are you able to walk?
걸을 수 있나요?
It's dawn
새벽이다
Go back and take a nap
돌아가서 낮잠을 자세요
Father is coming out soon
아버지가 곧 나오신다
The little one has delivered the dinner as you asked.
당신이 요청한 대로 그 작은 아이가 저녁 식사를 배달해 주었습니다.
Let her eat enough so she can sleep well
충분히 먹게 하여 잠을 잘 수 있게 해주세요
Yes, the younger one retreated first.
응, 동생이 먼저 물러났어.
Looking downcast
우울한 모습
If this continues, something will happen to my family's ancestors as well.
이런 일이 계속되면 우리 가족의 조상에게도 무슨 일이 일어날 것입니다.
It would be better to just die
그냥 죽는게 나을듯
If you disappear without a sound
소리 없이 사라지면
I'm afraid it will cause a commotion
소란을 일으킬까봐
Tell the maid of this household
이 집 가정부에게 말해요
You have to go back to your parents’ house
부모님 집으로 돌아가야 해.
Mother’s family?
어머니의 가족?
So where is this place?
그럼 이곳은 어디에 있나요?
Is it your in-laws?
당신의 친척입니까?
Abominable
혐오스러운
Why did you change to this place?
왜 이 곳으로 바꾸셨나요?
This is my home since yesterday
어제부터 여기가 내 집이야
Having said that
그렇게 말하면서
Why do you help me change into mourning clothes?
왜 상복으로 갈아입도록 도와주나요?
Has anyone died in this family?
이 가족 중에 죽은 사람이 있나요?
Ah that...
아 그거...
What about this...
이건 어떡하지...
Someone is coming
누군가 오고 있어요
If you continue here, you will be discovered. I will hide first.
여기서 계속하면 발견될 것이다. 내가 먼저 숨을게.
Damn it, why is it that guy?
젠장, 왜 저 사람이야?
What are you doing here so early in the morning?
이렇게 이른 아침에 여기서 뭐하세요?
Wrong
틀렸어
why did you come here
왜 여기에 왔나요?
I'll collect the body
시체는 내가 수습할게
It seems I came too early
너무 일찍 온 것 같아
It’s over. How could he be the second young master of this family?
끝났습니다. 그가 어떻게 이 가문의 두 번째 젊은 주인이 될 수 있었습니까?
Corpse?
시체?
Why do you come here to find corpses...ah?
시체를 찾으러 왜 여기까지 오는데...아?
Aren't corpses usually placed behind the incense table?
보통 향대 뒤에는 시체를 두지 않나요?
Why don't you go to the sarangcha to find...?
사랑차에 가서 찾아보시는 건 어떨까요...?
are you kidding me now
지금 장난하는 거야?
No...
아니...
It seems you have come to the wrong place
장소를 잘못 찾아오신 것 같습니다
Hurry over there...
서둘러 거기로...
It almost turned me off
그게 날 거의 꺼지게 만들었어
What should I do if I die before I get trampled?
짓밟히기 전에 죽으면 어떻게 해야 합니까?
Hello
안녕하세요
What about me?
나는 어떻습니까?
I don’t quite understand the context of this conversation right now.
지금은 이 대화의 맥락을 잘 이해하지 못합니다.
Is this what a husband who just married his wife should say?
이제 막 결혼한 남편이 이런 말을 해야 할까요?
Husband?
남편?
what to do
무엇을 해야할지
The newlyweds were so inseparable that it was too late
신혼부부가 너무 뗄래야 뗄 수 없어서 너무 늦었어
What about trampling?
짓밟는 건 어때?
It seems that there was a dispute between the couple last night.
어젯밤에 부부 사이에 말다툼이 있었던 것 같습니다.
who is your husband
당신의 남편은 누구입니까?
Who else could it be?
또 누구일까요?
You standing in front of me
내 앞에 서 있는 너
I'm going crazy, really
미칠 것 같아, 정말
Your joke has gone a bit too far since just now
방금 전까지 농담이 좀 지나쳤어
How does this look like a joke?
이게 어떻게 농담처럼 보이나요?
are you crazy
너 미쳤어?
The husband you mentioned passed away last night
당신이 언급한 남편이 어젯밤에 세상을 떠났어요
How could he die?
그가 어떻게 죽을 수 있었습니까?
If this mourning dress was worn because the husband died,
남편이 죽어서 이 상복을 입었다면,
Then who are you?
그렇다면 당신은 누구입니까?
answer
답변
grandson of the deceased
고인의 손자
Grandson?
손자?
It's so late. Why are you here?
너무 늦었어요. 당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Just think that I'm here to discipline the family. How about
내가 가족을 징계하기 위해 여기에 왔다고 생각하십시오. 어때?
So that’s when…
그럼 그때는…
wait a moment
잠깐만요
Since he already has grandchildren
그에겐 이미 손자가 있기 때문에
My husband must be at least sixty or seventy years old.
내 남편은 최소한 예순, 일흔은 되어야 합니다.
Is this marriage reasonable?
이 결혼은 합리적인가?
you are really crazy
너 정말 미쳤어
Still awake now
지금도 깨어 있어요
I want to…
나는하고 싶다…
It should be the latter...right?
후자여야 하는데... 그렇죠?
I think I should have been hit hard
세게 때렸어야 했다고 생각해요
will temporarily lose consciousness
일시적으로 의식을 잃게 됩니다
Thanks to you, I was able to figure out the situation, Mr. Sun Tzu.
덕분에 손자씨 상황을 파악할 수 있었습니다.
Also
또한
I just mistook you for my husband.
방금 당신을 내 남편으로 착각했어요.
hope you can never forget
당신이 결코 잊지 않기를 바랍니다
Even if you only have that thought for a moment
그 생각이 잠시라도
It all makes me feel extremely humiliated
이 모든 것이 나를 극도로 굴욕스럽게 만든다
It seems you are back to normal
원래대로 돌아오신 것 같군요
But what about this attitude?
하지만 이런 태도는 어떻습니까?
young master
젊은 주인
All of you on the list came to express your condolences.
귀하와 귀하의 동료 모두가 조의를 표하기 위해 왔습니다.
Go quickly
빨리 가세요
The mourner cannot leave the party for too long...
애도자는 파티를 너무 오랫동안 떠날 수 없습니다.
Stop
중지
Are you feeling well?
기분은 괜찮나요?
Do you still remember that you were carried back last night?
어젯밤에 다시 끌려간 일을 아직도 기억하시나요?
Probably remember
아마 기억할 거야
Anyway, this woman's body
아무튼 이 여자의 몸은
There is no need to come forward to receive condolences
조의를 받으러 나올 필요는 없어
Don't let anyone in or out during the funeral.
장례식 중에는 누구도 들어오거나 나가지 못하게 하십시오.
I'm going back to my parents' house
부모님 집으로 돌아갈 거예요
Just pretend you don't know
그냥 모르는 척 해
yes
응
Hong Eun-jo, come out
홍은조야 나와라
Leave over the wall
벽 너머로 떠나
I don't want to stay in this home for a second
나 이 집에 단 한 순간도 머물고 싶지 않아
Where are you going?
어디로 가시나요?
No one will pass this path
이 길은 누구도 지나갈 수 없을 거야
Just say it here
여기서 말해보세요
The marriage is just like what you just heard
결혼은 방금 들었던 것과 똑같아
That gentleman is my nominal husband
그 신사는 나의 명목상의 남편이다
They passed away as soon as they got married last night
그들은 어젯밤에 결혼하자마자 세상을 떠났습니다
Maybe you think this is unreasonable
어쩌면 당신은 이것이 불합리하다고 생각할 수도 있습니다.
But it's common for people like me
하지만 나 같은 사람들에게는 흔한 일이야
Sorry, I lied to you and said that the second young master of that family was my husband.
미안해요, 그 집의 두 번째 젊은 주인이 내 남편이라고 거짓말을 했어요.
I thought it would be good for both of us to say that.
나는 우리 둘 다 그렇게 말하는 것이 좋을 것이라고 생각했습니다.
This way you can give up sooner
이렇게 하면 더 빨리 포기할 수 있다
I'll have less trouble
트러블이 덜할텐데
Why haven't you said a word since just now?
방금 이후로 왜 한 마디도 하지 않았나요?
You have to say something to solve the situation at hand.
당면한 상황을 해결하려면 말을 해야 합니다.
Because I don't know what to say
무슨 말을 해야 할지 모르겠으니까
I kept thinking along the way
가는 내내 계속 생각났어
But can't say a word
하지만 한 마디도 할 수 없어
I'm nothing to you
나는 너에게 아무것도 아니다
Not qualified to vent this anger
이 분노를 터뜨릴 자격이 없어
This may be a choice you made under difficulty
힘들게 내린 선택일지도 모르지만
I can't blame easily
쉽게 탓할 수 없어
But I don’t want to pretend to understand what you said, “This kind of marriage is very common.”
하지만 “이런 결혼은 흔하다”는 말을 이해하는 척하고 싶지는 않습니다.
and absurdly agree with
그리고 터무니없이 동의한다
What makes me most angry now is
지금 나를 가장 화나게 하는 것은
Because I'm not in my body
내 몸에 내가 없으니까
Even if I have to drag you out of that damn place,
널 그 빌어먹을 곳에서 끌어내더라도
Can't do it
할 수 없어
So we have to change our bodies back first.
그러므로 우리는 먼저 우리 몸을 다시 바꿔야 합니다.
I can understand it as waiting for the change to come back
변화가 다시 오기를 기다리는 것으로 이해할 수 있습니다.
Will you carry out what you just said?
방금 말한 대로 이행할 건가요?
you understand very correctly
당신은 매우 정확하게 이해하고 있습니다
I'm even thinking
나는 심지어 생각하고있다
How to destroy the family that facilitated this marriage?
이 결혼을 촉진한 가족을 어떻게 파괴할 수 있습니까?
Only then can I vent my anger
그래야만 분노를 발산할 수 있다
What I'm most angry about is
내가 가장 화가 나는 것은
Don't know anything about this
이것에 대해 아무것도 모른다
And stupidly praying for you
그리고 어리석게도 당신을 위해 기도해요
Being stupid enough to put embroidered shoes into your hands
수놓은 구두를 손에 쥐어줄 정도로 멍청한 짓
So I’ll say the ugly things first.
그러니까 먼저 못생긴 말부터 할게요.
I will be even more ruthless next time
다음엔 더 무자비해질 거야
Not even a moment's hesitation
한 순간의 망설임도 없이
Let’s end this topic here.
이번 주제는 여기서 마치겠습니다.
You didn't have to get married
꼭 결혼할 필요는 없었어
You can also tell me
당신은 또한 나에게 말할 수 있습니다
I don't think I need to give up on the marriage
결혼을 포기할 필요는 없을 것 같아요
Not so pitiful that he needs help from others
다른 사람의 도움이 필요할 정도로 불쌍하지는 않다
Although people who are bedridden
누워있는 사람들임에도 불구하고
It is deeply regrettable to die on the wedding day
결혼식 날 죽는 것은 정말 안타까운 일이다
But I want to say that at least I can be in that home from now on
하지만 적어도 앞으로는 그 집에 있을 수 있다고 말하고 싶어요
Live without worries
걱정 없이 살아요
Until we suddenly switch bodies
갑자기 몸이 바뀔 때까지
So the first priority is to return to our respective bodies first.
그러니 우선 각자의 몸으로 돌아가는 게 우선이다.
You continue to enjoy your life while I go and do whatever I want
내가 가서 내가 원하는 것은 무엇이든 하는 동안 당신은 계속해서 인생을 즐기고 있습니다.
If we want to successfully implement each other's goals, let's do this
서로의 목표를 성공적으로 구현하고 싶다면 이렇게 해보자
Just treat it as a temporary consensus.
그냥 일시적인 합의로 취급하세요.
Mom, are you okay?
엄마, 괜찮아요?
If the great master passes away
위대한 스승이 돌아가시면
What should our Eunjo do?
우리 은조는 어떻게 해야 할까요?
She became a widow at a young age
그녀는 어린 나이에 과부가 되었다
Can't you take her back?
그녀를 다시 데려갈 수는 없나요?
She is married
그녀는 결혼했다
Now he belongs to that family
이제 그는 그 가족의 일원이 되었습니다
Even if I die, I will die in that home. What can I do?
나는 죽어도 그 집에서 죽을 것이다. 어떻게 해야 하나요?
Unless she wants to run far away
그녀가 멀리 도망가고 싶지 않다면
Run away?
도망가?
This is something I've never seen in a book
이건 책에서 본 적 없는 일이야
Not to mention legends or folktales
전설이나 민담은 말할 것도 없고
No matter how you think about it, this doesn't look like something humans do.
아무리 생각해도 이건 인간이 할 짓이 아닌 것 같다.
Do you mean God did it?
하나님이 하셨다는 뜻인가요?
That's divine punishment, right?
그건 신의 징벌이겠죠?
At least I'm sure it's definitely not a blessing
적어도 분명 축복은 아닐 거라 확신해
I won't be angry
난 화내지 않을 거야
You really tell me the truth
당신은 정말로 나에게 진실을 말해줍니다
Have you done nothing wrong recently?
최근에 아무 잘못도 없었나요?
No
아니요
Even if I did something wrong
내가 뭔가 잘못했어도
Why do you have to be punished with me?
왜 나와 함께 벌을 받아야합니까?
The point is, why is it you and me?
요점은 왜 당신과 나입니까?
When is your birthday?
당신의 생일은 언제입니까?
Bingwu year Gengzi month Guihai day
빙무년 겐자월 귀해일
It’s different from my sun pillar.
내 태양기둥과는 다르다.
If you want to think in a superstitious direction, then be thorough.
미신적인 방향으로 생각하고 싶다면 철저하게 생각하십시오.
follow me
나를 따라와
You are a medical woman. Don’t you have a medical explanation?
당신은 의료 여성입니다. 의학적 설명이 없나요?
Be quiet
조용히 하세요
It will be taboo
금기시될 거예요
There's a virgin ghost living inside you
당신 안에는 처녀 유령이 살고 있어요
can you see me
나를 볼 수 있나요
Can you really see anything?
정말 아무것도 보이지 않나요?
So you are a grown man
그럼 당신은 어른이군요
He understands women’s hearts better than women, right?
그는 여자보다 여자의 마음을 더 잘 이해하죠?
This guy…
이 사람은…
He's a playboy, right?
그 사람 플레이보이죠?
Get up
일어나
Let’s do a ritual
의식을 치르자
I can help you exorcise ghosts
귀신을 쫓아내는 걸 도와드릴 수 있어요
Hello
안녕하세요
I'm not trying to kick this woman out of my body
나는 이 여자를 내 몸에서 쫓아내려는 것이 아니다
Do you want to try doing some rituals?
몇 가지 의식을 해보고 싶나요?
As long as the soul leaves the body
영혼이 육체를 떠나는 한
At least try other methods
적어도 다른 방법을 시도해 보세요
What if I never come back?
내가 다시는 돌아오지 않으면 어쩌지?
Are you planning to go for a walk in Huangquan?
황취안(Huangquan)으로 산책을 갈 계획이신가요?
Could it be that it's not a soul exchange?
영혼 교환이 아닐 수도 있나요?
But body swap?
그런데 바디스왑?
So we should start with the body, right?
그럼 몸부터 시작해야겠죠?
sincerely
진심으로
hold religiously
종교적으로
Do you feel it?
느껴지시나요?
Not at all
별말씀을요
Didn’t you say you need to use your body?
몸을 써야 한다고 하지 않았나요?
How can anything change if you just move your hands?
손만 움직이면 어떻게 변할까요?
Otherwise, what should I do?
그렇지 않으면 어떻게 해야 합니까?
Are you sure you have no selfish motives?
당신은 이기적인 동기가 없다고 확신합니까?
What selfishness?
무슨 이기심?
(I don’t know when they started looking at the same place)
(언제부터 같은 곳을 보기 시작했는지는 모르겠습니다)
Show some sincerity too
진심도 좀 보여줘
what
뭐
Good
좋아
(Even if you want to hide it, it will still gradually expand)
(숨기고 싶어도 점차 확대됩니다)
(Want to hug you Loving you)
(안아주고 싶어 사랑하고 있어)
(I don’t want to let go for a moment)
(한시도 놓치고 싶지 않아)
(Every day is filled with us)
(매일이 우리로 가득 차 있어)
(all seem to shine beautifully)
(모두 아름답게 빛나는 것 같아요)
Did you feel anything?
느낀 점이 있나요?
Yes very loud
네 아주 시끄러워요
Is my heartbeat so loud?
내 심장소리가 그렇게 큰 걸까?
are you kidding
농담하는 거야?
Very pleasant
매우 기분 좋음
After the change comes back, you can listen to it as much as you want
변경된 내용이 다시 돌아온 후에는 원하는 만큼 들을 수 있습니다.
I don’t think I’m exchanging my body for it.
나는 내 몸을 그것과 교환하고 있다고 생각하지 않습니다.
When did we exchange?
우리 언제 교환했어요?
Last night when people decided?
어젯밤에 사람들이 결정했을 때요?
Will it be replaced by then?
그때쯤이면 교체되나요?
Is it all just a nightmare one night?
이 모든 것이 어느 날 밤의 악몽에 불과한 걸까요?
It's time for people to decide
이제 사람들이 결정할 시간이다
nightmare…
악몽…
It seems to have become longer
좀 더 길어진 것 같은데
Abominable
혐오스러운
You just said it doesn't seem to be man-made, right?
방금 인공이 아닌 것 같다고 말씀하셨죠?
Then it’s useless no matter how hard one tries
그러면 아무리 노력해도 소용없어요
Doesn't it matter if we continue to live like this?
계속 이렇게 살아도 상관없지 않나요?
I don’t even know when I will switch back
언제 다시 전환할지는 모르겠지만
So you are here
그래서 당신은 여기 있습니다
There's a lot of commotion happening at your place
당신의 집에서 많은 소란이 일어나고 있어요
It's you again
또 너야
Then I won’t say much more
그럼 더 말 안 할게.
You've already finished scolding with your expressions
표정으로 꾸짖는 건 이미 끝났어
what
뭐
Anyone who looks at it can tell that it was me who was dragged out
누가 봐도 끌려간 건 나였음을 알 수 있다
why do you look like you want to blame me
왜 나를 비난하려는 것처럼 보이나요?
If you want to scold me, I'll scold this guy who won't let me go.
네가 나를 혼내고 싶다면 나를 놓지 않는 이 사람을 혼낼 것이다.
"This guy"?
"이놈"?
You always have to think about whose mouth this is, right?
누구의 입인지 항상 생각해야겠죠?
As long as it's right, it doesn't matter which mouth you say it from.
그것이 맞다면 어느 입에서 말하는지는 중요하지 않습니다.
I said...
내가 말했지...
Ignore him and talk to me
그 사람 무시하고 나랑 얘기 좀 해
What? No, I’m asking you to speak out.
무엇? 아니요, 말씀해 달라고 요청하는 것입니다.
Yes
예
There's a lot of commotion in the palace right now
지금 궁에 소란이 많이 일어나고 있습니다
why
왜
The Concubine orders you to enter the palace immediately
후궁은 즉시 궁으로 들어가라고 명령합니다.
Why is the empress like this?
황후는 왜 이럴까요?
Convey to empress
황후에게 전하다
Now I am unable to enter the palace due to circumstances that do not allow it.
지금은 사정이 허락하지 않아 궁에 들어가지 못하고 있습니다.
Now is not the time for you to speak
지금은 네가 말할 때가 아니다.
He only listens to your orders. Tell him.
그는 당신의 명령에만 귀를 기울입니다. 그에게 말해주세요.
"You"?
"너"?
The empress has even been on a hunger strike since last night
황후는 어젯밤부터 단식투쟁을 하기도 했습니다
Say you won't eat anything until you come
너 올 때까지 아무것도 먹지 않겠다고 말해
Because of me?
나 때문에?
Otherwise, who would it be because of?
그렇지 않으면 누구 때문일까요?
What kind of trouble did this body cause?
이 몸은 어떤 문제를 일으켰나요?
No dignity or character at all
존엄성도 성격도 전혀 없음
He doesn't even have the status to speak
그 사람은 말할 자격조차 없어
It happened that I revealed my identity in this body
우연히 이 몸으로 정체를 드러냈는데
You first go and report to the Maharaja that your Majesty will enter the palace.
당신은 먼저 가서 마하라자에게 폐하께서 궁전에 들어오실 것이라고 보고하십시오.
I said
나는 말했다
It seems you are going to go there
거기로 가실 것 같군요
Your Majesty
폐하
Your Majesty... Your Majesty?
폐하... 폐하?
Yes, it's you
응, 바로 너야
Your Majesty
폐하
So
그래서
Are you the second son of His Royal Highness?
당신은 전하의 둘째 아들입니까?
Yes
예
Is he also the younger brother of the current Lord?
그 사람도 현 영주의 남동생인가요?
This means you are...
이것은 당신이 ...
The prince of North Korea?
북한의 왕자?
you seem surprised
너 놀란 것 같아
Is it because she has a good appearance as rumored?
소문대로 외모가 좋아서일까요?
We woke up in the palace at that time
우리는 그 시간에 궁전에서 일어났어요
I thought you already had a idea in your mind
난 당신이 이미 마음속에 생각을 갖고 있다고 생각했어요
Why don't you speak?
왜 말을 안 해요?
Because I don’t know what to say either
나도 무슨 말을 해야할지 모르겠으니까
The words I wanted to say but disappeared
하고 싶었던 말은 사라졌지만
It seems to be because of the intimidating effect of the word "Maharaja"
'마하라자'라는 단어가 주는 위협적인 효과 때문인 것 같다.
What's wrong with you? It doesn't look like you.
왜 그래? 당신처럼 보이지 않습니다.
I'm thinking about every word I've said so far
나는 지금까지 내가 한 말을 모두 생각하고 있어요.
Have I committed treason?
내가 반역을 저질렀나요?
If I commit it, will you give me a chance to atone?
내가 죄를 지으면 속죄할 기회를 주실 수 있나요?
Just do as you originally did
그냥 원래 하던 대로 하세요
Do you want me to continue to offend you so that I can be beheaded?
내가 참수될 수 있도록 계속해서 당신을 화나게 하길 원하시나요?
are you making fun of me
너 나를 놀리는 거야?
I've never met anyone remotely related to the royal family.
나는 왕실과 원격으로 관련된 사람을 만난 적이 없습니다.
However, one day the core of the royal family
그러나 어느 날 왕실의 핵심
Even when the highest person appears before me
가장 높은 분이 내 앞에 나타나도
Aren't you going to panic?
당황하지 않을 건가요?
That's why I didn't say anything
그래서 난 아무 말도 안 했어
Because everyone doesn’t know how to treat me after hearing this
이 말을 듣고 다들 날 어떻게 대해야 할지 모르니까
And feel uncomfortable
그리고 불편함을 느끼세요
It’s not because the name “Maharaja” is so great that we hide it
마하라자라는 이름이 너무 거창해서 숨겨서가 아니다.
It's an order from now on
지금부터 명령이다
I order you to continue to treat me as you did before.
나는 당신이 예전처럼 계속해서 나를 대할 것을 명령합니다.
You are not allowed to disobey
당신은 불순종하는 것이 허용되지 않습니다
Because when I woke up, I was in the palace
왜냐면 내가 일어났을 때 나는 궁전에 있었거든
I thought you were an official who came to the government office to report
관공서에 신고하러 온 공무원인줄 알았는데
Who would have thought that it was your home?
누가 그곳이 당신의 집이라고 생각했을까요?
In this North Korea, are there more than fifteen people in the palace?
이 북한에서는 궁궐에 사람이 15명 이상 있나요?
There should be more than ten
10개 이상이어야 합니다.
After all, I have something to hide, so I’m not qualified to say anything.
결국 저는 숨길 게 있어서 아무 말도 할 자격이 없거든요.
But there are still difficulties now
하지만 지금도 여전히 어려움이 있습니다
If you don't want to, just refuse.
원하지 않으시면 그냥 거절하시면 됩니다.
Wait, your mother is starving in the palace.
잠깐만요, 당신 어머니는 궁전에서 굶주리고 계십니다.
But did you actually say such unfilial words?
그런데 실제로 그런 불효한 말을 했나?
After all, that body is not very filial.
결국 그 몸은 그다지 효도적이지 않습니다.
So you want me to...
그래서 당신은 내가 ...
Let the former mother of the country starve to death?
이 나라의 전 어머니를 굶어 죽게 놔두겠습니까?
It’s not that I don’t want to go, I just want you to give me an alternative.
가고 싶지 않은 게 아니라 대안을 제시해 주셨으면 좋겠어요.
It's going to be daybreak, hurry up
새벽이 될 테니 서두르세요
Just do as I say
내가 말한 대로만 하세요
First put your hands behind your back
먼저 손을 등 뒤로 눕혀주세요.
Keep your waist straight at all times
허리는 항상 곧게 유지하세요
Look as arrogant as possible
최대한 오만하게 보이세요
what
뭐
Didn't you say he would enter the palace?
그 사람이 궁궐에 들어간다고 하지 않았나요?
The adults are here
어른들은 여기 있어요
It turns out that she is the concubine.
그녀가 첩이라는 것이 밝혀졌습니다.
Don't be timid. Just do as he says.
소심해하지 마세요. 그가 말한 대로만 하세요.
Anyway, the words that came out of my mouth
아무튼 내 입에서 나온 말은
None of it represents my opinion
그 어느 것도 내 의견을 대변하지 않습니다
The Queen Mother is getting older
왕모님은 점점 늙어가시네요
He seems to be becoming more and more stubborn.
그는 점점 더 고집스러워지는 것 같습니다.
Why not eat or drink?
왜 먹거나 마시지 않습니까?
Wouldn't it hurt this beautiful appearance?
이 아름다운 모습을 해치지 않을까요?
Where did you spend the night the past two days?
지난 이틀 동안 어디서 밤을 보내셨나요?
What a surprise
정말 놀랍습니다
She actually had no reaction to my frivolous words
그녀는 내 경박한 말에 사실 아무 반응도 하지 않았다
It’s just a place with the sky as its home and the wind as its mattress.
하늘이 집이고 바람이 매트리스인 곳일 뿐이다.
Are you also friends with that woman?
너도 그 여자랑 친구야?
Woman?
여성?
Well...you never mentioned women. Who is she talking about?
글쎄요...당신은 여자에 대해 언급한 적이 없어요. 그녀는 누구에 대해 이야기하고 있습니까?
I don't know either
나도 모르겠어요
Who else knows?
또 누가 알겠어요?
I saw it with my own eyes last night
어젯밤에 내 눈으로 봤어
You hold the hand of a girl from unknown family and play in the palace
가문을 알 수 없는 소녀의 손을 잡고 궁전에서 놀아요
Concubine, you misunderstood
첩, 당신은 오해했습니다
That girl has nothing to do with me
그 여자는 나랑 아무 관계도 없어
Yesterday was the first time we met
어제가 우리가 처음 만났던 날이었어
No, it shouldn’t be the first time
아니, 처음이면 안 돼
Is this the second time?
이번이 두 번째인가요?
Don't let me act rashly with that face
그런 얼굴로 함부로 행동하게 하지 말아줘
Keep up the good demeanor of a great king
위대한 왕의 좋은 태도를 유지하십시오
Now that I've seen it
이제 봤으니
Tell me which family you are a daughter of
당신이 어느 집안의 딸인지 말해주세요
Play dumb
멍청하게 놀아라
I don't know. I really don't know.
모르겠어요. 나는 정말로 모른다.
Do you want me to capture all the ladies in North Korea before you open your mouth?
입 열기 전에 북한 아줌마들을 다 잡아 달라고?
Said it was just a chance meeting and spending the night together
그냥 우연히 만나서 함께 밤을 보낸 거라고 했어
Don't know her name
그녀의 이름을 모른다
It's just a chance meeting and spending the night together
그저 우연히 만나서 함께 밤을 보내는 것일 뿐이야
what
뭐
Have you fallen in love like a common man?
평범한 남자처럼 사랑에 빠졌나요?
Because they are just ordinary people in the city.
그들은 도시의 평범한 사람들이기 때문입니다.
what did you say
뭐라고 했어?
you guy
너네
I feel deeply frightened that my son has become like this.
내 아들이 이렇게 됐다는 게 너무 두렵다.
That's not what I meant
내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었어
I mean, as a common citizen, I feel deeply frightened.
일반시민으로서 정말 두렵습니다.
As a king of a country, he cannot be a model of a gentleman.
한 나라의 왕으로서 군자의 본보기가 될 수 없습니다.
What are you still doing standing there? Call the doctor quickly.
아직도 거기 서서 뭐하고 있나요? 빨리 의사에게 전화하세요.
You are obviously not in good health, why do you go on a hunger strike to this point...
분명 건강도 좋지 않은데 왜 이 지경까지 단식을 하느냐...
What to do if something goes wrong
문제가 발생하면 어떻게 해야 할까요?
Your Majesty is very worried about you.
폐하께서는 당신을 매우 걱정하고 계십니다.
I kept chattering all day long until my little one even memorized it.
아이가 다 외울 때까지 하루 종일 계속 수다를 떨었습니다.
Yeah, that's it
응, 바로 그거야
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
take your hands away
손을 떼세요
bad guy
나쁜 놈
How could you spend one night with someone's precious daughter and then abandon her?
어떻게 누군가의 소중한 딸과 하룻밤을 보내고 그 딸을 버릴 수 있겠습니까?
I never taught you this
난 너한테 이런 걸 가르쳐준 적 없어
If you still know how to respect me
아직도 나를 존중할 줄 안다면
At least you should show some reflection.
최소한 어느 정도 반성하는 모습을 보여야 합니다.
I will reflect on it
반성하겠습니다
I don’t think I’ve seen you as a palace maid before.
나는 당신이 궁녀로 있는 것을 본 적이 없는 것 같아요.
Small?
작은?
The young one has just entered the residence of the Maharaja.
그 젊은이는 이제 막 마하라자의 거주지에 들어왔습니다.
what is your name
당신의 이름은 무엇입니까
Xiao Wei Hong Shi
샤오웨이홍시
Hong Shi?
홍시?
What's wrong? What's the problem?
무슨 일이야? 무엇이 문제인가요?
Please express your condolences
애도를 표해주세요
It’s all because women who shouldn’t be in the house are like this.
다 집에 있어서는 안 될 여자들이 그러하기 때문이다.
If you want a drink, come out
한잔하고 싶으면 나와서
Zai Yi
자이
No need for wine
와인은 필요없어
That one...
그거...
It’s Eunjo’s mother
은조 엄마예요
I wonder if I can let her meet secretly
그녀를 몰래 만나게 해줄 수 있을까
She said she wanted to go back to her parents' house, so I kept silent.
친정으로 돌아가고 싶다고 해서 나는 침묵을 지켰다.
It's all my fault for making you disliked by the concubine.
첩이 당신을 미워하게 만든 것은 모두 내 잘못입니다.
Don't take it to heart, it won't be a matter of a day or two anyway.
마음에 두지 마십시오. 어쨌든 하루 이틀 만에 문제가 되지는 않습니다.
We can't be together all the time
우리는 항상 함께 있을 수는 없어요
I will also take this body back to your husband's house before tomorrow morning.
이 시신도 내일 아침까지 남편 집으로 가져가겠습니다.
You can also hide in another courtyard during the mourning period
애도 기간 동안 다른 안뜰에 숨을 수도 있습니다.
But there's a funeral tomorrow
그런데 내일 장례식이 있어요.
No matter what, I have to show up.
무슨 일이 있어도 나는 나타나야 해.
can you do this for me
나한테 이거 해줄 수 있어?
Didn’t you say you must protect me?
나를 보호해야 한다고 하지 않았나요?
Although I don’t know what I can protect with this marriage.
이 결혼으로 무엇을 지킬 수 있을지는 모르겠지만.
But can you do it alone?
그런데 혼자서 할 수 있나요?
Be sure to do it
꼭 해보세요
Protect each other's lives and find a way to get back on track.
서로의 생명을 보호하고 정상으로 돌아갈 수 있는 방법을 찾으세요.
Then you have to stay up late with me today
그럼 오늘은 나랑 늦게까지 자야지
who is she
그녀는 누구입니까?
Why pretend to be a palace maid?
왜 궁녀인 척 하는 걸까요?
They have been in the room for three hours. What on earth are they doing?
그들은 3시간 동안 방에 있었습니다. 도대체 그들은 무엇을 하고 있는 걸까요?
That's right. Your Majesty has an order.
좋아요. 폐하께 명령이 있습니다.
Any information leaked to outsiders will be severely punished
외부인에게 유출된 정보는 엄벌에 처해질 것입니다.
The character illustrations around you should look like this.
주변의 캐릭터 일러스트는 이런 모습이어야 합니다.
The rest depends on my superb adaptability.
나머지는 나의 뛰어난 적응력에 달려있습니다.
There's something about that...
뭔가가 있는 것 같아...
Is there anything else you want to explain?
또 설명하고 싶은 게 있나요?
It's been hard for me to open my mouth to you during this time.
그동안 당신에게 입을 열기가 힘들었습니다.
what
뭐
our each other's bodies
우리 서로의 몸
Just pretend you can't see it
그냥 못 본 척 해
Ah
아
Now is the time to draw the line
이제 선을 그릴 시간이다
You've finished watching everything you should see, right?
보아야 할 건 다 보셨죠?
No, I didn't see anything.
아니요, 아무것도 보지 못했습니다.
This is not what I saw
내가 본 건 이게 아닌데
It’s seen by the person in front of me, so it’s you who sees it
앞에 있는 사람이 보이니까 보는 건 너야
Sounds like I looked at it carefully once
한번 유심히 살펴봤던 것 같은데
And my body too
그리고 내 몸도
It was not you who touched it, but my own hand.
그것을 만진 것은 당신이 아니라 내 손이었습니다.
You got it
당신은 그것을 얻었다
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
But I am the one who has the memory
하지만 그 기억을 가진 사람은 나야
Sir, don’t you also know?
선생님, 당신도 모르시나요?
I'm very confident
나는 매우 자신감이 있다
I haven't seen it
나는 그것을 본 적이 없다
I said it wasn't with my eyes
내 눈엔 아니라고 했어
Go ask Dazao to come
가서 다자오에게 오라고 해라
what does it mean
그게 무슨 뜻이야?
Are you avoiding my question?
내 질문을 피하고 있나요?
I start walking back from here
여기서부터 다시 걷기 시작해
Someone might see it accidentally
누군가는 우연히 보게 될지도 모르지만
Good
좋아
jujube
대추
No, Judge Xu
아니요, Xu 판사님
Please follow the Lord at all times
언제나 주님을 따르십시오.
Notice if he is trembling with fear
그가 두려움에 떨고 있는지 주목하세요
Is the behavior reckless?
행동이 무모한가?
Did you eat on time?
제 시간에 식사하셨나요?
Or whether you are alone at night...
아니면 밤에 혼자 있는 건지...
cry secretly
몰래 울다
Please pay close attention to
주의 깊게 살펴보시기 바랍니다.
No need to remind you
상기시켜줄 필요 없어
This is my duty
이것이 나의 의무이다
Just know
그냥 알아둬
Although other people's emotional affairs...
남의 감정적인 일이지만..
should not interfere excessively
지나치게 간섭하면 안 된다
But if you dare to use the Maharaja
하지만 감히 마하라자를 사용한다면
Or let him get hurt
아니면 그 사람이 상처받게 놔두세요
I will definitely take action myself by then
그때까지는 나도 꼭 조치를 취하겠다
Have you been acting cool in private?
개인적으로 쿨하게 행동해왔나요?
what
무엇
I was almost fascinated by you
난 거의 당신에게 매료됐어요
wait a moment
잠깐만요
everyone stop thinking
다들 생각을 멈추세요
Mother
어머니
young master
젊은 주인
Why did you come here?
왜 여기에 왔나요?
Where did you go, girl?
어디 갔어?
The young master talks without thinking
젊은 스승은 아무 생각 없이 말한다
Even if he talks nonsense, don't pay attention to it.
그가 말도 안 되는 말을 하더라도 신경 쓰지 마세요.
He is very kind and not a bad person
엄청 친절하고 나쁜 사람도 아닌데
Do you wish you were left out?
당신이 제외되기를 바라나요?
How do you know my wish
내 소원을 어떻게 알아?
what
뭐
Master, it will be good if she comes back safely
주인님, 무사히 돌아오시면 좋을 것 같아요
The patient I was caring for was not feeling well, so I went to visit him.
제가 진료하던 환자분의 몸이 좋지 않아 면회를 다녀왔습니다.
Thank you for taking so much trouble.
많은 수고를 해주셔서 감사합니다.
You're just so nosy anyway
어쨌든 넌 참 참견이 심해
Do you still want to be a medical woman now?
지금도 여전히 의료인이 되고 싶나요?
The person who has passed away has passed away
돌아가신 분이 돌아가셨습니다.
Those who are alive must live on
살아있는 사람은 계속 살아야 한다
I see you are not sad at all
그러고 보니 당신은 하나도 슬프지 않군요
It's like waiting for the eldest father of this family to pass away
이 집안의 큰 아버지가 돌아가시기를 기다리는 것과 같습니다.
Mother, look
어머니, 보세요
This girl doesn't answer
이 여자는 대답이 없어
I understand
나는 이해한다
The reason why you concealed your husband's identity was that you insisted on getting married.
남편의 정체를 숨긴 이유는 결혼을 고집했기 때문이다.
It's all for a reason
다 이유가 있는 거야
You already knew he would pass away
당신은 그가 세상을 떠날 것이라는 것을 이미 알고 있었습니다
No wonder you must marry even if your mother objects.
어머니가 반대하더라도 결혼을 해야 하는 것은 당연한 일입니다.
Did I even hide this from my family?
내가 이것을 가족에게도 숨겼나요?
Still want to escape?
아직도 탈출하고 싶나요?
Actually, you want to act like a lady from another hall, right?
사실 다른 홀 아줌마처럼 행동하고 싶잖아요?
Yes, whatever you say
응, 뭐라고 해도
Mother, let’s go
어머니, 가자
We worry about her for nothing
우리는 그녀에 대해 아무것도 걱정하지 않습니다
chat with me
나랑 채팅해
She is someone who only worries about me and my family.
나와 내 가족만을 걱정하는 사람입니다.
So I insisted on getting married against my mother’s wishes?
그래서 나는 어머니의 뜻과는 반대로 결혼을 고집한 걸까?
Once you make up your mind, you will definitely do it
한번 결심하면 반드시 해낸다
No one can stop you, so I didn’t try to hold you back.
누구도 막을 수 없으니 나도 널 막으려 하지 않았다.
I understand too
나도 이해해
You raised your daughter to be very stubborn
당신은 딸을 아주 고집쟁이로 키웠어요
in retrospect
돌이켜보면
Maybe that's why I didn't stop you
어쩌면 그래서 내가 널 말리지 못한 건지도 몰라
As a mother, I am really shameless.
엄마로서 정말 뻔뻔해요.
I'm asking this because I really don't understand.
정말 이해가 안가서 이렇게 질문드립니다.
Mother’s daughter…
엄마의 딸…
How should I feel now?
이제 기분이 어떠해야 할까요?
poor child
가난한 아이
Of course you won't know
물론 당신은 모르겠죠
Because it's all buried
다 묻혀있으니까
Buried in the words "It doesn't matter"
상관없어'라는 말 속에 묻혀
Your Majesty
폐하
It has been confirmed that she has entered the house
집에 들어간 것으로 확인됐다.
Thank you for your hard work. Go and rest.
여러분의 노고에 감사드립니다. 가서 쉬세요.
That…
그…
When I followed your whereabouts, I discovered something
너의 행방을 추적하던 중 뭔가를 발견했어
Do you know that woman?
그 여자를 아시나요?
Marrying someone?
누군가와 결혼하나요?
In the end, it was discovered
결국, 발견됐어
What a surprise
정말 놀랍습니다
I was hoping at least he wouldn't know
나는 적어도 그 사람은 모르길 바랐다.
Your Majesty, are you okay?
폐하, 괜찮으세요?
It's okay
괜찮아
It must be okay
괜찮겠지
Does it mean I always put myself last?
내가 항상 나 자신을 맨 마지막에 둔다는 뜻인가요?
it's all my fault
다 내 잘못이야
I only teach you to be patient and hold on.
나는 단지 인내심을 갖고 버티도록 가르친다.
Sorry Eunjo
미안해 은조
It seems that this body should be protected the most.
이 몸이 가장 보호되어야 할 것 같습니다.
It's my mother, right?
우리 엄마 맞죠?
No, don't do that
아니, 그러지 마세요
Take it
가져가
This is the money I borrowed from the Consul of the Art Museum.
미술관 영사님께 빌린 돈입니다.
Why did you give me this money?
왜 나에게 이 돈을 주었나요?
Although like you said
비록 당신이 말한 것처럼
After becoming the concubine of a powerful man, I don’t have to worry about food and clothing.
나는 유력자의 첩이 된 후에는 먹을 것과 입을 것을 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
I don’t have to worry about money and my life is very stable.
돈 걱정도 없고 생활도 매우 안정적이에요.
Dan Enzu
단 엔주
Even if life is good
인생이 좋아도
Even if life is really good
인생이 정말 좋아도
If one day you feel regret and want to run away
언젠가 후회하고 도망치고 싶다면
Just take this money and go
그냥 이 돈 가지고 가세요
I heard that as long as you escape to the Ming Dynasty, no one will catch you.
명나라로 도망치면 아무도 잡을 수 없다고 들었습니다.
Leave me and the Superintendent alone
나와 감독관은 내버려둬
Go far away
멀리 가세요
Promise your mother about this, okay?
이건 엄마한테 약속해, 알았지?
If it were the original well-behaved daughter
원래 착한 딸이었다면
I will definitely agree
나는 확실히 동의할 것이다
But now I have to make another promise
하지만 이제 또 다른 약속을 해야 해
what is
무엇입니까?
I won't let a drop of water get on your hands
손에 물 한 방울도 묻지 않게 해줄게
How did that go?
어떻게 됐나요?
We used the name of the thief Ji Tong
도둑 Ji Tong의 이름을 사용했습니다
Ji Tong?
지통?
They are the thieves who robbed Da Si Jian's warehouse.
그들은 Da Si Jian의 창고를 훔친 도둑들입니다.
Da Sijian also mentioned that person before he passed away
Da Sijian도 죽기 전에 그 사람을 언급했습니다.
I hate that thief so much
난 그 도둑이 너무 싫어
No one should doubt
누구도 의심해서는 안 된다
black sword
검은 검
What's going on in the Robbery Hall?
강도 홀에서는 무슨 일이 벌어지고 있는 걸까요?
They are searching for the whereabouts of people around Da Si Jian
그들은 Da Si Jian 주변 사람들의 행방을 찾고 있습니다.
Don't leave this to anyone else
이 일을 다른 사람에게 맡기지 마세요
Watch it yourself
직접 시청해 보세요
Yes
예
Is this North Korea what you got?
이것이 북한이 당신이 가지고 있는 것입니까?
you guy
너네
Aren't you afraid of divine punishment?
신의 형벌이 두렵지 않습니까?
If the Lord knows
주님께서 아시면
You will definitely be punished by the three tribes
너는 반드시 세 지파의 벌을 받을 것이다.
punished with lingchi
링치로 처벌받다
If you want to live
살고 싶다면
Give me half of the country of Korea
한국 땅의 절반을 주세요
The so-called greed...
이른바 탐욕..
When a fool becomes greedy, he is seeking his own death.
어리석은 사람이 탐욕을 부리면 자기 죽음을 추구하는 것입니다.
Remember to engrave this lesson on your rotting flesh
썩어가는 육체에 이 교훈을 새겨두세요
You may meet other royal families during the day
낮에는 다른 왕실 가족을 만날 수도 있습니다
While everyone is asleep
모두가 잠든 사이
Memorize the location of the palace
궁전의 위치를 기억해 두세요
Zhang Shurong
장 슈롱
She is Jinlu who has only heard rumors
소문만 들었던 진루 입니다
It's medicinal
약용이에요
Where did it come from?
그것은 어디에서 왔습니까?
First time I smell this smell
처음으로 이 냄새를 맡는다
Although inhaling smoke from burning medicinal herbs can alleviate symptoms
약초를 태울 때 나오는 연기를 흡입하면 증상이 완화될 수 있지만
If there is so much smoke that it spreads outside the house, it will be dangerous.
연기가 너무 많아 집 밖으로 퍼지면 위험합니다.
Who would treat this way?
누가 이런 식으로 대하겠습니까?
Kangnyeongjeon
강녕전
His Royal Highness's sleeping quarters
전하의 침실
No matter what happens, I cannot see His Highness.
무슨 일이 있어도 저는 전하를 볼 수 없습니다.
No
아니요
There's a time and a place to meddle in other people's business, right?
다른 사람의 일에 개입할 때와 장소가 있잖아요?
Your Majesty?
폐하?
Can't let others know I've been here
내가 여기 있었다는 걸 다른 사람들에게 알릴 수 없어
Yes
예
The treatment going on in the dormitory...
기숙사에서 진료중..
It’s so noisy…
너무 시끄러워요…
The little one is deeply frightened, Your Highness.
어린 아이는 몹시 겁을 먹었습니다, 전하.
Are you suffering from sores?
상처로 고통받고 있나요?
Yes
예
What's the matter
무슨 일이야?
Please be quiet
조용히 해주세요
What should I do if I wake up His Highness later?
나중에 전하를 깨우면 어떻게 해야 합니까?
Palace…
궁전…
Next?
다음은?
Do you want to confirm the medicinal materials?
약재를 확인하시겠습니까?
Yes, Your Highness
예, 전하
The little one goes out for a walk
작은 아이가 산책하러 나간다.
Your Highness, the smoke must be dispersed outside the house first.
전하, 먼저 연기를 집 밖으로 내보내야 합니다.
You guys come here to help. We need to ventilate it first.
너희들은 도움을 주기 위해 여기로 온다. 먼저 환기를 시켜야 합니다.
You guys move faster
너희들은 더 빨리 움직여
what are you doing
뭐하는거야?
Your Highness, no matter what kind of treatment
전하, 어떤 대우를 받더라도
Excessive use will cause side effects
과도하게 사용하면 부작용이 발생합니다
Do you want to refute the doctor's prescription?
의사의 처방을 거부하고 싶나요?
Of course I don't dare
물론 감히 그럴 수는 없다.
But according to my experience
하지만 내 경험에 따르면
For sores, you must drink water boiled from bezoar and honeysuckle.
종기에는 위석과 인동덩굴을 끓인 물을 마셔야 합니다.
Apply ointment and ventilate frequently to facilitate recovery
연고를 바르고 자주 환기시켜 회복을 촉진하십시오.
I hope you don't rely on new medicinal materials
새로운 약재에 의존하지 마시길 바랍니다.
Existing treatments must be tried simultaneously
기존 치료법 동시 시도 필요
It seems you know my symptoms very well
내 증상을 잘 아시는 것 같군요
That makes you look so disappointed
그러면 당신이 너무 실망한 것 같군요
Because it’s not a terminal illness
불치병이 아니기 때문에
what
뭐
That's not what I meant by being small
내가 작다는 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었어
Just in the smoke
그냥 연기 속에
Seeing you in pain
괴로워하는 너를 보니
what did you say
뭐라고 했어?
Although the sore wound is not big, it is easy to ignore it
아픈 상처는 크지 않아도 무시하기 쉽다
However, it is easy for patients to have such minor injuries affect their daily lives.
그러나 환자는 이러한 경미한 부상으로 인해 일상생활에 영향을 받기 쉽습니다.
Over time, it will affect your life
시간이 지나면 인생에 영향을 미치게 됩니다
As a result, patients suffering from disease
그 결과 질병으로 고통받는 환자들은
My heart will gradually become sick
내 마음은 점점 아프게 될 거에요
I just want to lighten some of your burdens
너의 짐을 조금이라도 덜어주고 싶을 뿐이야
That's out of proportion. You're meddling in other people's business.
그건 비율이 맞지 않네요. 당신은 다른 사람의 일에 간섭하고 있습니다.
It sounded so sincere that I almost choked up.
너무 진지해서 숨이 막힐 지경이었다.
Back off
물러서라
Yes, Your Highness
예, 전하
I actually saw His Highness the Lord
나는 실제로 주님 전하를 보았습니다.
Is his relationship with the Maharaja not good?
마하라자와의 관계가 좋지 않은 걸까요?
Let's go back to the dormitory
기숙사로 돌아가자
The time has come for people to decide...
이제 사람들이 결정할 시간이 왔습니다.
I was so flustered that I didn’t even think about Ji Dong’s side.
너무 당황해서 지동이 편은 생각도 안 나더라고요.
Have you caught the real culprit?
진짜 범인을 잡았나요?
Still in the period of confinement and unable to leave the palace
아직도 감금상태에 있어 궁궐을 떠나지 못하고 있다.
What to do
해야 할 일
Are you saying it's not Ji Tong?
지통이 아니라고 하던데요?
Isn’t it written in the blood book?
혈서(血書)에 기록되지 아니하였느냐
We're investigating people who have a grudge against sinners
죄인에게 원한을 품은 사람들을 조사하고 있습니다.
Do you think my adults are sinners?
우리 어른들이 죄인이라고 생각하시나요?
It would be unjust enough just to die.
그냥 죽는 것만으로도 부당한 일이겠죠.
He actually regarded him as a sinner
그는 실제로 그를 죄인으로 여겼습니다.
You bad guys
나쁜 놈들아
You send her home
당신은 그녀를 집으로 보냅니다
Yes
예
let me go
날 보내줘
Ji Tong?
지통?
catch up
따라잡다
Ji Dong, this damn guy
지동아 이 빌어먹을 놈아
No shooting allowed, must be captured alive
총격 금지, 생포해야 함
Sir
선생님
Report this matter to your Majesty immediately
즉시 폐하께 이 문제를 보고하십시오.
obey
복종하다
I actually got a glimpse of North Korea's most traitorous official
실제로 북한의 가장 반역적인 관리를 엿볼 수 있었습니다
Du Chengzhi Ren Shiheng’s family secrets
Du Chengzhi Ren Shiheng의 가족 비밀
Zhang Shurong?
장수롱?
Why are you here dressed like this?
왜 여기서 이런 옷을 입고 있나요?
Lord Daoyue seems to know the truth about the medicinal materials
도월공은 약재에 대한 진실을 알고 있는 것 같습니다.
Lord Daoyue?
다오웨 경?
yes
응
He took away all the incense
그는 향을 모두 가져갔다.
What's going on
무슨 일이야?
How could they mention my banned account?
어떻게 내 금지된 계정을 언급할 수 있나요?
Ji Tong was arrested
지통이 체포됐다
Oops, lucky boy... lucky boy?
이런, 럭키 보이... 럭키 보이?
I heard he was caught by the Robbery Hall
강도회관에 잡혔다고 들었는데
What should people do?
사람들은 무엇을 해야 합니까?
Enzu
엔즈
are you from the cemetery
당신은 묘지에서 왔나요?
Are you feeling well?
기분은 괜찮나요?
much better
훨씬 좋아
But what does it mean that Ji Dong was arrested?
그런데 지동이 체포됐다는 건 무슨 뜻일까?
I just heard about it too
나도 방금 그 얘기 들었어
I heard that Ji Tong was hit by an arrow yesterday.
어제 Ji Tong이 화살을 맞았다는 소식을 들었습니다.
what
뭐
Enzu
엔즈
Did the Lord disappear out of thin air again?
주님이 또 허공에서 사라지셨나요?
Seeing that there was no movement inside, I went in to take a look.
내부에 아무런 움직임이 없는 것을 보고 안으로 들어가 살펴보았습니다.
But found that the person was no longer there
그런데 그 사람이 더 이상 거기에 없다는 걸 알게 됐어요
The case is settled
사건은 해결됐다
Yes
예
Wait
잠깐
Doctor Hong
홍박사
Is this person Ji Dong?
이 사람이 지동인가요?
The adults folded the bedding and night clothes so neatly?
어른들이 침구와 잠옷을 이렇게 깔끔하게 개어놨나요?
Not only that
그뿐만 아니라
The adults even cleaned
어른들은 청소도 하시고
Something is wrong
뭔가 잘못됐어
Go to the Maharaja immediately
즉시 마하라자(Maharaja)로 가세요.
What happened?
무슨 일이 일어났나요?
scared me
겁이 났어
Sir, where have you run to?
선생님, 어디로 달려가셨나요?
In the inner hospital, I went to boil the medicine and deliver it to the concubine’s palace.
내원에서는 약을 끓여서 후궁에 전달하러 갔습니다.
what
뭐
I feel like this is the only way to alleviate the guilt in my heart
내 마음 속 죄책감을 덜어주는 유일한 방법인 것 같아
Then why fold the bedding and night clothes?
그렇다면 침구와 잠옷은 왜 접어야 할까요?
Easy to fold when you wake up
일어났을 때 쉽게 접을 수 있음
Why didn't you tell us?
왜 우리에게 말하지 않았나요?
Did you put on the clothes yourself?
옷은 직접 입으셨나요?
Yes, I want you to sleep more
응, 더 자고 싶어
if we make any mistakes
우리가 실수를 하면
please tell us directly lord
주인님 직접 말씀해주세요
What's wrong
무슨 일이야?
Send the doctor in immediately. Immediately.
즉시 의사를 보내십시오. 즉시.
What's going on with you guys?
너희들에게 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까?
Your Majesty
폐하
Officer Park from the Robbery Bureau asked for an audience.
강도국의 박 경관이 청중을 요청했습니다.
Has the news gotten out?
뉴스가 나왔나요?
Ji Tong died on the spot after being hit by an arrow
Ji Tong은 화살을 맞고 그 자리에서 사망했습니다.
Ji Tong is dead?
지통이 죽었어?
Where is the fake lucky boy?
가짜 행운아는 어디에 있나요?
Disposed of
폐기됨
Clean it up yourself
스스로 청소하세요
obey
복종하다
Buried
묻힌
Have a good trip, Ji Tong
여행 잘 다녀오세요 지통님
Let's go Yes
가자 응
Maybe the real murderer will come and take away the body of the fake Ji Tong
어쩌면 진짜 살인자가 와서 가짜 지통의 시신을 빼앗아갈지도 모른다.
Still collected neatly
그래도 깔끔하게 모아놨다
This is…
이것은…
Do I really have that?
나한테 정말 그런 게 있는 걸까?
Are they really collected neatly?
정말 깔끔하게 정리되어 있죠?
I really can't stand it
정말 못 참겠어
So what should I do?
그러면 어떻게 해야 합니까?
Is it because I don’t know how to read people’s emotions? Did I come in too early?
내가 사람의 감정을 읽을 줄 모르기 때문일까? 내가 너무 일찍 들어왔나?
From now on, count to ten at the door before coming in.
이제부터 집에 들어오기 전에 문앞에서 10까지 세세요.
The way you look at me
당신이 나를 보는 방식
Shaking very violently
아주 격렬하게 흔드는 중
what do you want
당신은 무엇을 원합니까?
I want you not to do anything
아무것도 하지 않았으면 좋겠어
Your majesty keeps getting in my way for some reason
폐하께서 무슨 이유인지 자꾸 방해하시네요
Your Majesty's maid, please stay.
폐하의 하녀님, 머물러 주십시오.